in Ukraine, the possible mobilization force
на Украине мобилизационная сила
is 5 million, approximately, well, 5 million
возможная - это 5 млн примерно ну 5 млн
soldiers Yes, roughly speaking, in the Russian
воинов Да грубо говоря в Российской
Federation, the possible mobilization force
Федерации возможная мобилизационная сила
is approximately 30 million Yes, you know,
- это 30 млн примерно Да знаете знаете В
what is your mistake, error, look at what you
чём у вас ошибка ошибка смотрите что вы
take into account Only mathematics and do not
берёте в расчёт Только математику а не
take physics for example  chemistry, biology, there
берёте например физику химию биологию
is a Hars installation,
вот есть установка харс
okay, good
Да ладно добрый
afternoon, good evening, I’m from Ukraine, the city of
день Добрый вечер я из Украины город
Khmelnitsky, where you’re from, I know very well
Хмельницкий Вы откуда я прекрасно знаю
where you’re from  I’m getting acquainted I’m from Ukraine, the
откуда вы я знакомлюсь Я из Украины
city of Khmelnitsky You’re
город Хмельницкий Вы
from Siberia,
откуда Сибирь
the city of
город
Minusinsk,
Минусинск
which
какой
Minusinsk I don’t know, some small
Минусинск не знаю маленький какой-то
town,
городок
yes, yes, I realized that they forgot in chat
да ну да понял что тут забыли в чат
roulette, in fact, I’ll explain to you
рулетке на самом деле я вам объясню
By the way, I’ve watched you on tube more than once
Кстати я вас смотрел на тубе не раз
already I’m here for chat roulette  I’m
уже Я здесь чат рулетки нахожусь на
actually here Well, well, no more than two weeks
самом деле Ну ну недельки две не больше
I was just wondering Well, in general,
мне просто было интересно Ну вообще
judging by the video, the opinion of all sorts of bloggers is the
вот Судя по видео мнение всяких блогеров
situation Yes,
ситуации сво Да
let’s say and So I’m interested in how
допустим и Вот мне интересно вот как вот
you are in general  sit and talk about it
вы вообще сидите и рассуждаете об этом
all, just like we sit and talk and
обо всём как мы сидим и рассуждаем да
look, in order to turn on the
смотрите для того чтобы включить
thought process, you need to think.
мыслительный процесс так нужно подумать
So our neurons begin, there are some
Так у нас начинают нейроны там какие-то
electrical impulses that go
электрические импульсы идут
to the World Cup in the east, as we think as we
ится в ЧМ восто как мы думаем как мы
do, now I understand perfectly how it works  the
сечас я прекрасно понимаю как работает
human brain and in the World Cup Then you
человеческий мозг а в ЧМ Тогда
know the question about provocative all sorts of things
вопрос о провокационных всякие знаете
Let's formulate the question again
Давайте ещё раз сформулируйте вопрос
Briefly formulate the question Clearly and
коротко сформулируйте вопрос Чётко и
briefly I want to see the opinion of
коротко мне охота посмотреть мнение
one and the other side about open
одной и второй стороны о
source software This is a statement And the question
СПО это утверждение А вопрос В
What is the question from famous
чём от известных
bloggers What is the
блогеров так вопрос В чём
question Well, let’s say I’ve watched your video
вопрос Ну допустим я ваше видео смотрел
more than once
уже не раз
Yes, you’re arguing there, and
Да вот вы там рассуждаете да там вы
roughly speaking you’re a well-read person there,
грубо говоря Вы начитанный человек там
maybe a lawyer, I don’t know,
возможно юрист не знаю
but you know most of the people in these 2
но вот знаете большинство людей за эти 2
weeks Who I met in the chat  roulettes Yes, they seemed from the Ukrainian Well, I
недели Кого я встретил чат рулетки Да с
don’t know Well,
показались Ну не знаю Ну как
somehow I understood Even some Even
так-то понял Даже некоторые Даже
some don’t understand ordinary mathematics
некоторые обычную математику не понимают
It’s cool I can’t understand at all But you
прикольно вообще не могу понять А вы
understand ordinary mathematics And
обычную математику понимаете А Обычная
you know ordinary mathematics  What is the agreement
математика знаете В чём сходится
in the numbers or in the numbers 45 and 25, which
э в цифрах или в чис 45 и 25 что больше
will be more? What do you think,
будет Как вы думаете
that 145 and 25, which will be more? It depends on
что-что 145 и 25 что будет больше Смотря
what
чего
millions if 145 million and 25 million Yes,
миллионов если 145 млн и 25 млн Да мне
look, it’s hard for me to answer But I
Смотрите мне тяжело ответить Но у меня
have this assumption that 145  million
есть такое предположение что 145 млн
will be more than 25 million Yes
будет больше чем 25 млн Да
Look at the statistics approximately Yes this is
Смотрите по статистике примерно Да это
no secret to anyone in Ukraine the
никому не секрет на Украине
mobilization force is possible 5
мобилизационная сила возможная 5
Well 5 million soldiers Yes roughly speaking in the
Ну 5 млн воинов Да грубо говоря в
Russian Federation  possible
Российской Федерации возможная
mobilization force is 30
мобилизационная сила - это 30
million Yes, you know, what is your mistake,
млн Да знаете знаете В чём у вас ошибка
mistake, look at what you take into account
ошибка смотрите что вы берёте в расчёт
Only mathematics and don’t take, for example,
Только математику а не берёте например
physics, chemistry, biology, for example,
физику химию биологию так например
Let’s look at physics and chemistry,
Давайте вот посмотрим про физику и химию
there is a Hars installation, which
вот есть установка харс Да которая Одним
can
прилётом может
bury with one arrival  there are about 300 mathematicians in the Makeyevka vocational school.
похоронить в макеевском ПТУ порядка 300
That is, from Russia they
математиков Вот то есть из России они
come there from these 145 million. Yes,
приходят там вот из этих 145 млн Да
such crowds come  There
приходят такие толпы математиков вот в
was such a massive recruitment of mathematicians at the Makeyevka vocational school.
макеевском ПТУ очень такой был массовый
Yes, they had an open day
набор Да прям у них был день открытых
and Ukrainian chemists and physicists
дверей и украинские химики физики с
using the technology of Western chemists and
помощью технологии западных Химиков
physicists. Yes, they sent
физиков Да отправили
them this, let’s say,
им такое скажем
a work of art. Yes, which
произведение искусства Да которое
is called a rocket from highmore. So, uh, they
называется ракета от хаймор Вот и ээ они
showed that in itself  mathematics is
показали что сама по себе математика
just like mathematics, it’s good at
просто как математика так Она хороша в
numbers, yes, but when it goes in conjunction with
числах да но когда она идёт в связке с
chemistry and physics and other sciences,
химией и физикой и другими науками так
then it turns out  this Synergy is how it
тогда получается вот эта Синергия так и
turns out that several mathematicians in
получается что несколько математиков в
conjunction with physicists and chemists so
связке с физиками и с химиками так
send, let’s say,
отправить скажем так в Академ отпуск
a lot of mathematicians who have no
очень много математиков которые без
knowledge of physics and
знаний физики и
chemistry to the Academy. Well, yes, the sun
химии Ну да также сонце тоже
can also be Well, look, if we take the
може Ну смотрите если мы возьмём вот
military potential of the West because you  you
военный потенциал Запада потому что вы
’re not just fighting with Ukraine, you’re fighting
же воюете не просто с Украиной Вы воюете
with the entire collective West, there’s
со всем коллективным западом
actually a conflict going on with Russia,
правда происходит конфликт с россий
Ukraine, who’s supplying us, look who’s supplying
укра кто нам поставляет Смотрите кто
us and supplying us  the whole rich
нам да нам нам поставляют весь богатый
world is supplying weapons against us, poor,
мир поставляет оружие против нас бедная
impoverished Russia, which cannot produce
нищая Россия которая не может произвести
some kind of Armata tank, you have
какой-то танк армата вот у вас есть
such an
такой танк
Armata tank, you know honestly, it exists, but I don’t
армата знаете честно он есть но я не
know. It is in How can I
знаю Он есть в
tell you a
А как вам сказать
prototype, that is, like this?
опытный образец то есть вот вот так
Look at the matter  The fact is that yes, you have a
Смотрите дело в том что да у вас очень
lot of mathematicians.
много математика
Yes, I haven’t seen. That’s the point,
Да я не видел Вот вот в том-то и дело
you have 145 million in mathematicians, but
что у вас 145 млн в математиках так но
there are no physicists there.
нету вот каких-то физиков нету там
There are a lot of chemists there.
Химиков есть очень много философов у вас
So, your school of philosophy is
так вот философская школа Среди ваших
very well developed among your mathematicians. They
математиков очень сильно развита Вот они
know that you have Armata tanks and
знают что у вас есть там танки армата
some kind of wonder waffles. Yes, but for
ещё какие-то вондер вафли Да но на поле
some reason they are not on the battlefield, yes, that is, let’s
боя их почему-то нет да то есть а
say the Western school. Yes, the scientific school is
скажем Западная школа Да научная она
more practical.  so that is, she not
более практична так то есть она не
only relies on mathematics, but for
только делает ставку на математика а вот
example, they are bringing in biologists there right now, and
например пригоняют там вот сейчас
this is an experiment on biologists,
э это в попытер есть на Биологов
for example, who know how to
например которые с леопардами умеют
handle leopards, so here are the trainers
обращаться так вот дрессировщики
By the way, many
леопардов очень у нас кстати многие
mathematicians
математики
have retrained leopards and now they are grazing
переквалифицировало и сейчас выпаса
and
и
when a bunch of mathematicians are running with spears. Yes, and
когда бежит куча математиков с копьями
trainers are leading such a
Да а на них дрессировщики ведут такую
pack of leopards on them, so I would say I
свору леопардов так то это я бы сказал я
wouldn’t envy you If you were a
бы вам не позавидовал Если вы были
mathematician in this
математикой в этой
scheme But tell me, here you are  Do you seriously believe
схеме А скажите а вот вы серьёзно верите
that 200 leopards in
в то что 200 леопардов го
Ukraine 18 they turned the tide of
Украине 18 они перевернули ход
the war no
войны нет
yes yes no yes Why
да да нет да А почему вы ушли из
you left Kherson Wait, if if the course of the war were turned upside down Yes, let’s say look, the Russian army would not get closer, get closer, I don’t argue, gradually but steadily press closer and B date You’re a mathematician, so uh, I’m not a mathematician Well, we don’t Wait you are one of 145 million of these mathematicians, so in the Russian mathematical school, look if your army was moving in the direction of Kyiv and then something turned over and it started moving in the direction  from Kyiv, that is, the vector of movement Yes, the direction, it somehow turned upside down Yes, if your army went to Kherson and then went So it turned upside down, the course of the war turned upside down And why did it happen? Well, it’s interesting If it completely turned over something Yes, that’s how you reason that it’s as if everything is missing from the Russian army And where is it, you know, there is, but already Yes, look, there is very mathematically very interesting, so you’re like a mathematician So I finally met a kindred spirit Amiya, she somehow very quickly
начала идти в направление от Киева так
divided by
делится на
two by two is like Well by two how is it
два на два это как Ну на два как это
divided by two For example 10 times 2
делится на два Вот например 10 по 2
what
сколько
is probably four here and again
будет наверное четыре вот а ещё раз
divided by
поделить на
2 probably one and again divided by
2 наверное один а ещё раз поделить на
two mine Oh so look when
два мину О так вот смотрите когда
Math problem for the fourth
Задачка по математике для четвёртого
class means you love it. You
класса значит любите Вот вы в четвёртом
were solving
классе решали
problems in fourth grade. Well, of course, yes, for example, there,
задачи Ну конечно да вот например там
uh, X living occupiers got into Ukraine,
так ээ э в Украину влезла X живых
so yeah,
оккупантов так угу
uh, Y living ones got out of Ukraine  occupiers
ээ вылезла из Украины Y живых оккупантов
so yeah, of them Z Z you see Yes, in the half
так угу из них Z Z видите Да в полу
living there is a partially interesting letter yes yes
живых частично интересная буква да да
interesting Yes attention to the question where
интересная Да внимание вопрос а куда
did the difference between these occupiers
делась разница этих оккупантов
go Yes nowhere And where well look
Да никуда А куда ну как вот смотрите ещё
again we have Ukraine as a
раз есть у нас возьмём Украина как
black box goes in there and the occupiers
чёрный ящик туда заходит и оккупантов
creep out y  occupiers Yes, and Y is
выползает y оккупантов Да причём Y
somehow significantly smaller than
как-то значительно меньше
X, tell me, colleague mathematician, where
икса скажите мне коллега математик куда
did this
делась эта
difference go into oblivion, probably yes And into
разница в небытие наверное да А в
oblivion
небытие
[laughter]
[смех]
got it Cool This is this Wait, you see
понял Классно Это это Подождите видите
this is not mathematical but philosophically
это не математическо а философско
mathematical but not
математической ка не
being that is, if for example you were given an assignment, it
бытиё то есть если например вам поручили
means you work in a store,
значит вы работаете в магазине вам в
uh, 100,000 rubles came to the cash register, and in
кассу пришло ээ там 100.000 руб а
the evening for re-accounting It turns out there are
вечером на переучёт Оказывается там
20,000 rubles there, they ask you Where did it go
20.000 руб вас спрашивают А куда ушло
80.000 And you’re like this into
80.000 А вы такой в
oblivion yes It’s all possible by the way it
небытие да Это всё возможно кстати
turns out well where did these guys of yours go?
получается ну куда делись вот эти Ваши
I understand that you’re looking at
ребята Я так понял что смотрите
some
некоторые они там а остальные развернули
they are there and the rest turned the direction of movement and proudly left yes No they are now moving forward again Let's do it again Let's So the undercut means they left they somehow proudly turned around and clearly calmly marched away from the Kyiv region Sumy region Zhitomir Kharkov Odessa Nikolaev from Kherson from the Donetsk part there from the Va estuary There they expelled others too, that is, It was like this It was a friend of mine And now tell me where Where is your huge army  Now
огромнейшая армия сейчас
it’s breaking through in all directions,
прорывается по всем направлениям
little by little, in which all directions
потихоньку по каким всем направлениям
where Well, okay, look.
где Ну хорошо смотрите
But by the way, can I ask a question?
А вот кстати можно вопрос вот я вот
I’m really telling you this in all
реально я вам серьёзно говорю на полном
seriousness, I really don’t
серьёзе я вот прямо не
know. Wait, we’ll continue this
знаю Подождите мы дальше продолжим этот
question. If you don’t switch, but I
вопрос Если вы не переключитесь но я
want to ask you  question about A special correspondent
хочу задать вам вопрос по А спецкор
spondey, what is a special correspondent spondey of
спондей что такое спецкор спондей
Ukraine special correspondent What is a special correspondent
Украины спецкор Что такое спецкор
military special correspondent who have
военный спец корреспондент кто
you seen such a very large-scale
Вы видели такое очень масштабное прям
video like this for 2 hours
такое видео на 2 часа
about the war in Ukraine  who filmed it is
о войне ну на Украине который снимал оно
still written in English ri haven’t seen There’s
ещ по-английски пишется ри не видел Там
two episodes haven’t seen And you may have
две серии не видели А вы может быть
heard about this channel it was called
слышали о таком канале он назывался
before, but not before And now it’s called
раньше ну не раньше А сейчас называется
Friday haven’t
пятница не
heard not USA VM
слышал не США ВМ
sristvo for Asian countries for Asia Well, in
сри ство по странам Азии по Азии Ну в
general for  the whole world question What Let's Get
общем по всему миру вопрос В чём Давайте
closer to the point Now I want to
Ближе к делу Вот я прям сейчас хочу
ask you this question in detail, he
развёрнуто вам задать этот вопрос он
drowned for Russia Yes, he received a lot of
топил за Россию Да он получал огромные
money, earned all that now he is a
деньги зарабатывал всё такое сейчас он
war correspondent in Ukraine and he
военный корреспондент в Украине и он
even filmed this video with  your president
даже снимал это виде с вашим президентом
What is his last name Vorobyov, in my opinion or something? For the
Как фамилия его Воробьёв по-моему что
first time I hear it just In the tube just
ли Впервые слышу просто В тубе просто
type after the whole stream Rick another video
наберите после всего стрима Рик ещ видео
Rick Rick in English what is the question What will you
Рик Рик по-английски что вопрос В чём вы
find here, look he made a video about
найдёте вот смотрите он снимал видео о
what is allowed in some village
том что допустим в каком-то там посёлке
in Ukraine, yes, they killed m
на Украине да убили м мужчин
Ukrainian men. But look, I’m not an expert on
украинцев А смотрите вот я не эксперт по
video. Look, there are two corpses lying there. Yes,
видео Да вот смотрите лежат два трупа Да
he’s filming a video right from a correspondent
он снимает видео прямо корреспондент
like this, and together with the president, filming
такой а вместе с президентом снимать с
this with Zelensky  you will find the real video,
Зеленским это реальное видео вы его
watch it Come on man, give me a
найдёте посмотри Давай мужик давай мне
specific question, ask me a 5 minute
уже конкретно Вопрос задай ты 5 минут
story, there are two corpses lying there, there are two corpses lying
расска лежат два трупа лежат два трупа
Yes,
Да
men He films everything in detail and
мужчины Он снимает всё подробно и
look at the catch, so he says
смотрите в чём подвох вот он говорит что
that the Russian military, such bastards,
вот российские военные вот такие падлы
killed these two Yes  civilians and
убили вот этих двух Да мирных жителей и
look, one has boots that you will
смотрите вот у одного ботинки вы это
see in the video, absolutely clean, new ones,
увидите на видео абсолютно чистые новые
and the second one is covered in mud, which is like
А у второго в грязи который то есть
the question: how did it happen that
походил вопрос как так получилось то что
one walked in the mud?  the sky or
один в грязи ходил другой по небу что ли
something I have no idea I haven’t seen this video I do
там Понятия не имею Я не видел это видео
n’t even have an idea out of
даже не имею представле ради
curiosity you can
интереса можете мне вот прямо сейчас
show me these boots right now Show me these boots then I can at
Покажите вот эти ботинки я тогда могу
least say something And so you’re
что-то хоть сказать А так вы про
talking about some abstract boots
какие-то абстрактные ботинки говорите
No I told you the name  video I
Нет я вам назвал название видео я вам не
can’t send you a link right now, what do you want
могу сейчас ссылку скинуть что вы сейчас
from me now?
от меня
I’m just wondering, but in Ukraine they
хотите мне просто интересно а на Украине
like provocative videos. Well,
нравится провокационные видео Ну
send it and you like it.
скидывать и вот вам нравится
Yes, we have provocative videos, there’s a
Да у намо есть ели провокационные видео
very cool
есть очень такой прикольный
provocative one.  director Robert Magyar haven’t
провокационный режис Роберт мадяр не
heard of no, he also didn’t travel around Asia, of course he didn’t
слышали нет тоже он вот по Азии он не
travel. He
путешествовал конечно Он
went to Hungary somewhere there, he went to Austria
где-то там в Венгрию ездил там в Австрию
because he lived somewhere in Transcarpathia,
потому что он где-то на Закарпатье жил
that is, he was not a very famous
то есть был не очень известный такой
director, so he’s an amateur, but it’s like the
режиссёр так аматор вот а как бы
last one  he's been making very
последний год он снимает очень
cool videos like this for a year, and
прикольные такие видео причём
this one you said he's already filming
Вот этот который вы сказали он уже
after the fact, he's filming those
как-то постфактум снимает он снимает тех
who are already lying and dead. But this
кто уже лежит да Мёртвый А вот этот
Robert is a madman. Yes, he's  makes films about
Роберт мадяр Да он снимает фильмы про
those who are still moving, yes, that is,
тех кто ещё двигается да то есть
for example, they are moving, moving, and
например вот они двигаются двигаются а
then for some
потом по каким-то
reason unknown to science, mathematicians
причинам неизвестным науке математики
stop moving, yes, that
перестают двигаться да то
is, while these are there, there are just a
есть пока вот эти там как раз вот очень
lot of such videos where your mathematicians
много таких видео где ваши математики
are doing there in the form of uh  different graphs of
они там делают в виде ээ разных графиков
trenches Yes, there is someone in the form of a sine, so
окопы Да там кто-то в виде синуса так
there is someone doing there, just a
там делает кто-то делает там просто
straight line,
прямая вот
uh Well, there are different ones, there is a parabolic one,
ээ Ну там разные есть параболический
in short, I watched very different
короче вот я смотрел очень разные
mathematicians, so they make different shapes of trenches
математики так разные формы окопов
and this director  Magyar, in
делают и вот этот режиссёр мадяр он в
principle, he is not a mathematician, so he
принципе не математик так он больше
would say more there Physics and art, so
сказал бы там Физика и искусство так вот
he can show just talent, talent,
просто талант талант он может показать
with an example How to
на примере Как из простых ботанов
make simply awesome
математиков сделать просто офигенный
content from simple mathematician nerds, usually we know how it is
контент обычно у нас знаешь как
believed that Mathematics is some kind of
считается что Математика - это какое-то
boring thing  something about mathematics Yes,
вот скучно что-то про математику Да вот
they show mathematics, there are some
показывают математику вот какие-то там в
such nerds with glasses, the chairs there are not shaved,
очках такие ботаны стулы там не бритые
and this is very lively
да а это очень там очень такие живые
mathematicians, they say, they run
математики они скажем бегают какие-то
they solve some mathematical problems, so these ones
математические задачи решают так вот эти
run around these trenches like sine sine
бегают по этим окопам как синус синус
sine sine damn it's just a
синус синус блин просто
yoke a team of philosophers Yes, they are basically
иго команда философов Да они в принципе
trying to find a point on the graph Yes, for
пробуют найти точку на графике Да
example, burn And if you send a
например гори А если вот отправить
rocket yes yes Well, it's not a rocket they're simpler
ракету да да Ну там не ракету они проще
like they
типа они
there they hand over something to Dronov Yes, for example And
там Дронов что-то сдают Да например А
if the value of X is like this Yes, what
если значение X будет такое Да какое
will be the value of the function at this point X
будет значение функции в этой точке X
they threw it
кинули блин
a little shorter damn it didn’t work
немножко короче блин не получилось
Yes, you see You have the same thing  So,
Да понимаете У вас тоже самое есть Так
well, now you're hitting a stick with two
что Ну вы сейчас долби палку двух
ends. Wait,
кон Подождите
you, as a mathematician, should understand
п вы вы как математик должны понимать
that a stick can have more than two
что у палки может быть больше чем два
ends; it
конца
really can be a stick with three ends.
правда может быть палка с тремя концами
very
трёхконфорочная Мне было очень
interesting You promised to answer the
интересно Вы Вы же обещали ответить на
question Where are you advancing in all directions
вопрос Где же вы по всем направлениям
because here By the way,
наступает потому что вот Вот кстати
the question is now and will be in principle
вопрос сейчас и буде в принципе по
about this But you What do you think
поводу этого А вот вы Как вы считаете
is the situation in
какая Вот обстановка в
Bakhmut What kind of military operations are going on, well, well,
бахмуте Какая боевые действия идут ну ну
well, the whole situation is not
ну а полностью обстановка вы не в
normal, yes, that means there
нормально да значит
is a mathematical symposium in Bakhmut.
в в бахмуте происходит математический
So very
симпозиум Так там съехались очень
talented mathematicians from all over Russia gathered there.
талантливые математики со всей России
They recruited these mathematicians from all zones,
Там их по всем зонам набирали этих
so why did they
математиков так они Да за за
sit there for mathematical crimes?
математические преступления там сидели
- it turned out that after
почему-то оказалось так что после того
your army
как ваша армия
entered Ukraine from all directions and
зашла со всех направлений в Украину и
came out, remember this problem of ours, what
вышла вот помните эту нашу задачку что
went in X came out Y, it turned out that without a set of
зашло X вышло Y оказалось что без набора
mathematicians, in short  can’t cope Yes, and the
математиков уже Короче не справится Да и
army had to, there are no mathematicians, they
пришлось армии нету каких-то математиков
throw nerds, mathematicians are thrown into
бросают ботанов математиков бросают в
battle for such meat assaults Yes, and
бой на вот такие мясные штурмы Да и
so many have already been shown in the
столько вот уже показывали в
Krasnodar region, there’s just such a
Краснодарском это крае там прямо такое
cemetery of mathematicians, it’s exactly like that in the
кладбище математиков оно именно так в
shape of a rectangle, it’s exactly like
форме прямоугольника так ровненько такое
that, it’s possible  straight clear
так именно вот можно прям чёткой
rectangular shape so all angles are 90°, it’s
прямоугольной формы так все углы 90° вот
clear that mathematicians tried
видно что математики старались
mathematicians for mathematicians And then
математики для математиков Да и тут ж
there’s this  mathematics, look at this
вот такая математика смотрите вот этот
bakhmut, it is located from the invasion line,
бахмут он находится от линии вторжения
so I looked at the map and measured it. This is
вот я посмотрел на карте померил Вот это
12 km with a ruler on the map, that is, on
линейкой на карте 12 км то есть 24
February 24, 2022. The Horde invaded and
февраля 2022 года Орда такая вторглась и
how long has it been for 13 months? Yes,
за сколько это уже за 13 месяцев Да
more than a year, 13 months, they have advanced
больше года 13 месяцев продвинулась
only there by 12
только там на 12
km Yeah, at the cost of huge losses, you
км Угу ценой огромнейший потерь вы
understand that you blew up
понимаете что вы подорвали
yours no no, that’s not the case with ours, there
свою нет нет с нашей не так идт с нашей
are losses with ours too, but when you look when
тоже есть потери но когда смотрите когда
you have  they just drive
у вас гонят просто вот так
unprepared mathematicians just like that, just like that
неподготовленных математиков так просто
with two-edged sticks they drive
с двух концом палками гонят На
physicists and chemists into fortified positions, and
укреплённые позиции физиков и Химиков да
somehow the numerical superiority is far
то как-то численный перевес идёт далеко
from being in the direction of
не в сторону
mathematicians Well, perhaps
математиков Ну возможно
you Well, you claim that there are from some
вы Ну утверждаете что на там из каких-то
places And you generally know  who is Well,
мест А вы вообще в курсе кто вот Ну вот
who can be hired by VK Vad? Well, I think that
кого могут взять ВК Вад Ну я думаю что
different mathematicians are only those who,
разных математиков только те которые
let’s say, were not imprisoned, for example, for some kind of
скажем не сидели например за какие-то
mathematical
математические там
research. Well, you almost guessed there
исследования Ну вы почти угадали туда
They only take Volunteers. Even those
Берут только Добровольцев Даже те
who, roughly speaking, have one
которые грубо говоря им остался один
day left, but Volunteers, look. Wait,
день но Добровольцев смотри Подожди
dude, mathematics, mathematics, She is on her
чувак математика математика Она сама по
own. Voluntary science, have you
себе Добровольная наука ты видел
ever seen Who is anyone who would go to
когда-то Кто кто-нибудь кто пошёл бы
get an academic degree in mathematics
э учёную степень получать по математике
forcibly in mathematics, this is necessary in order to
принудительно математике это надо чтобы
go to  to study mathematics you just have to be
идти на математика учиться это надо быть
crazy That is, I have never seen a
просто крези То есть я не видел ещё ни
single person in my life who
одного человека в жизни да который
voluntarily went to be a
добровольно шёл быть
mathematician oh who was forced That
математиком ой который принудительно То
is, everything is at the call of the heart
есть все по зову сердца шли
Yes, I can even [ __ ] give my example of life
Да я даже блин могу свой пример жизни
without problems, but no
привести без проблем да не
need, from
надо то с
which you should have answered From which
каких вы должны были ответить С каких
all directions are you attacking?
это вы всех направлений наступает
Let's absolutely everyone, well, which ones
Давайте абсолютно всех ну каких
Let's look, to be honest, our
Давайте смотрите вот если честно наши
media here, let's talk like this on Kie,
СМИ сжи давай так на Кие выступаете
wait no  you said at all Tell me in
подождите не ты сказал на всех Скажи на
what direction tell me the directions such a city is
каких скажи направления такой город
like
такой
this I’m answering you look ours
такой вот я вам отвечаю смотрите наша
Here the media says 90% of
Вот СМИ так сказать говорит на 90% проди
the news on the Russian offensive And
новости по наступлению российской А
where did you get
откуда вы взяли
190 Well because I have friends there
190 Ну потому что у меня друзья там
ra 9
ра 9
90% of the Truth Let me ask you as a mathematician
90% Правды Давайте вот да как математик
Yes, look,
математика спрошу Да вот мы смотрите у
we have different mathematical schools So
нас у нас разные математических школ Вот
I, as a representative of the Ukrainian
я как представитель украинской
mathematical school, will ask you as a
математической школы вас как
representative of the Russian mathematical
представителя российской математической
school. Can you explain to me the
школы спрошу Можете мне объяснить
methodology of how you got 90% of the Truth,
методологию как Вы получили 90% Правды
here is the news How do you  found out that this is
вот есть новости Как Вы узнали что это
90%
90%
Truth Well, because this is true
Правды Ну потому что это правдивые
news that sends me
новости которые отправляют мне
time How did you get the number 90 How did you get the number 90
вре Как вы число 90 Как вы число 90
Tell me the formula by which you
получили Скажите формулу по которой Вы
got it  the number is 90 Because there is an
получили число 90 Потому что есть
error anyway, not what do you
погрешность всё равно не вот что на что
say? Say what you divided by to
скажите вот что на что вы поделили чтобы
get 90%. For example, why should I
получить 90% Вот например как зачем мне
divide if they directly send me the video
делить если мне напрямую скидывают видео
correctly? How did you determine that it is 90
правильно А как вы определили что это 90
and not
а не
85 because according to the news  according to
85 потому что по новостям по
regional ones, they still don’t tell the whole
региональным всё равно говорят не всю
truth, it won’t be shown there Why is 0
правду там не будет показывать Почему 0
92 or 88 How did you determine 90
92 или 88 Как вы определили 90 Потому
Because I like round numbers, you understand, and that
что я люблю круглую цифры понимаешь а то
is, you are a mathematician who simply knows everything
есть вы математик просто который всё
rounds up Well, of course, I got
округляет Ну конечно всё ко я понял
it all, I got it, wait, wait, I got it,
Понял подождите подождите я понял я
wait, I get it, you’re a mathematician who
подождите я понял вы математик который
just rounds everything up, yes. You can tell me then, so
просто всё округляет да Можете мне тогда
you rounded it
сказать Вот вы к числу 90 округлили его
up or down to the number 90, round it up
вот вверх или вниз округляй его вверх
m up up Yeah, I got it. So
м вверх вверх Ага понял Значит до
how much before rounding?  what was the number
округления сколько было какое было число
Truth
Правды
percentage Truth yes 90% A 10 Perhaps I
процентное Правды да 90% А 10 Возможно
didn’t understand What would be 90% of
не понял А сколько будет 90% от
100 90% of 100
100 90% от 100
Yes Are you serious now
Да А вы сейчас серьёзно
Yes 90% of 100 Yes 90% of 100 how many
Да 90% от 100 Да 90% от 100 сколько
will be how
будет
many will be
столько и будет
How many 90% of 100 Well in the number you
Сколько 90% от 100 Ну в число вот у вас
have 100 apples 90% of 100 apples - this is
есть 100 яблок 90% от 100 яблок - это
how much there
сколько
will probably be 90 90 of what
будет наверное 90 90
apples Okay And 90% of 90 how many
чего яблок Окей А 90% от 90 сколько
will be so that We finish our mathematical
будет чтобы Мы закончили математический
dispute
спор
90 of 9 90% of 9 how much
наш 90 от 9 90% от 9 сколько
will it be you decided for the evening mathematically
будет вы на вечер решили математико это
this is
это Элементарные
I understand elementary actions, you know, I’m not even
действия я понимаю познаете я даже не
going to answer this question for you
собираюсь вам на этот вопрос отвечать
because you don’t engage in such
потому что вы не занимаетесь такими
discussions here, how much will 90% of 90 be?
обсуждениями здесь сколько будет 90% от
because in
вы вы начали свой спич с того что в
Ukraine some people there don’t
Украине какие-то люди там математики не
know mathematics even there, here we are the final question
знают даже там вот мы финальный вопрос
round 90% of 90 what
раунд 90% от 90 сколько
will be 90% of 90 will be
будет 90% от 90 будет
90 no  think
90 нет думай
think take the number 90 Take
думай возьми число 90 Отбери от него
ten and 9 from it and tell me how much it will be these
деся и 9 и скажи сколько это будут эти
9 I don’t know math Come on How to
9 не знаю математи А ну давай А как как
find this percentage number How to find
найти вот э процентное число Как найти
How many percent Here you know that a
Сколько процентов Вот вы Ты знаешь что
complete 100%
полное 100% -
is 90 apples is  100% a certain
это 90 яблок - это 100% определённое
number is an unknown number of percent yes
число это неизвестное число процентов да
Well look Dava sleepily that Nati the number is
Ну смотри Дава сонно что Нати число это
multiplied by 100 and divided by the number
умножить на 100 и поделить на число
or vice versa
или наоборот
Well basically I  told you How much it will be
Ну в принципе я вам сказал Сколько будет
Look at the formula Ska tell me 90%
Смотри вот ты формулу Ска скажи вот 90%
of 90 I
от 90 сколько
don’t know how much it will be Well let’s think For
будет не знаю ну а давайте подумаем Вот
example, look Why look at the
например смотрите А зачем смотри
mathematical problem So in Russia
математическая задача так в России
every month 90% of its army remains From the
каждый месяц остаётся 90% от её армии От
current state, that is, uh, you  there were
текущего состояния то есть ээ у вас было
100 for example 100 army men Yes they became
100 например 100 армейцев Да их стало
shorter there 100 units in a month there
короче там 100 частей через месяц их
were 90 of them yes In 2 months there will be 90%
стало 90 да Через 2 месяца их станет 90%
of 90 how many there
от 90 сколько их
will be Yes there are a lot  there will be them, believe me Okay
будет Да много их будет поверьте Ладно
dude 81 will be everything come on Yes no Run No
чувак 81 будет всё давай Да нет Беги Нет
unfortunately but skoko Okay and how much
к сожалению а скоко Ладно а сколько
how much will it be Wait how much time do you have
сколько будет Подождите сколько у вас
if I'm wrong tell me how much
время если я не прав скажи мне сколько
then it will be 90% of
тогда будет 90% от
90 it will be 80 How did you wait and how did you
90 будет 80 А как ты подожди а как ты
find  that 80 will be the time, how much time do you have
нашёл что 80 будет время сколько у вас
2114 then how did you find what will be 80
2114 то как ты нашёл что будет 80
Wait
Подождите
wait
подожди
2114 2114 already
2114 2114 уже
2115 A  where is your city located, the city of Khmelnytsky between Ermolin and Staro Konstantinov and look at this, of course I don’t know where it is, but Kyiv is near you or not Well, it’s not really close and look at the wok first from Kyiv you go to Lyubor Yes, but from Lyubor to the west or to the east to the southwest to the southwest this means towards Europe look there I am now in Siberia what mi what minus what with Moscow and
2115 А где ваш город находится город
what And how is it that it is now
что А как так у вас сейчас
21:15 for us it is 21:15 Go and look, google
21:15 у нас 21:15 Зайди смотри гуглишь
for example Kiev time and see What
например киевское время и смотришь Какое
it should be for you at least a minute of 5
оно у вас должно быть минимум мину 5
hours I now have for summer
часов у меня сейчас у нас на летнее
time a minute in short but exactly Lord I
время мину короче а точно Господи я
forgot my life  Tell me, let's do this
забыл уня жизнь Раскажи давай так
Tell me, tell me how you got that
Расскажи расскажи мне как ты получил что
90% of 90 will be 80 and I
90% от 90 будет 80 и я
'll run through the usual deductions, which deductions
побегу обычными вычетами какими вычетами
Okay  your mathematics is at your best, not
Ладно математика у вас на высоте не
how high you are, I’m interested in But
какими выми мне интересно на высоте Но
in fact, I expected more from you
на самом деле я ожидал от вас большего
Well, look, I also expected more from
Ну смотрите Я тоже ожидал большего от
myself, but how could we start about mathematics, I wanted to talk about
себя но как бы мы начали про математику
politics, war, but you started
я хотел про политику войну но вы начали
about mathematics, so look, here I am
про математику поэтому смотрите Я вот
now I want to smoke, but out of respect,
сейчас хочу закурить но из-за уважения
so to speak, for the public, I won’t
так сказать общественности я не буду
take out a cigarette now, I’ll smoke
сейчас сигарету доставать я покурю
later, so I’m telling you, I
попозже так что я говорю вам Я от вас
expected a lot more from you personally.
вот лично от вас ожидал намного больше А
What did you expect, that’s
что вы ожидали вот
interesting, well, you know, your whole video
интересно ну знаете ваше все видео
provocative destruction of the next one
провокационное уничтожение очередного
there the next one the next one you
там очередного очередного очередного вы
want to say that you destroyed me I’m not a
хотите сказать что вы меня уничтожили не
well-read person
начитан человека которы
so I’m not going to fight with you
так я не собираюсь с вами сражаться по
How can I destroy you If we
Как я могу вас уничтожить Если мы с вами
didn’t fight with you
не сражались
you won’t even be able to defeat my intellect I
вы даже не сможете мой интеллект
can’t I can’t I can’t  you know, the
смогу не сможете не смогу это знаете
thing is that, for example, try to hit
Дело в том что например Попробуй попади
the void, for example, shoot, hit
в пустоту например Выстрели попади пулей
the void with a bullet, you can hit the void.
в пустоту сможешь попасть в пустоту Да
No, I’m telling you seriously. Yes, I’m
нет я вам говорю серьёзно Да я тоже
serious too. Have a good evening. Let’s
серьёзном хорошего вам вечера Давайте
run and get busy.
бежим заниматься
mathematics T the very mathematics
математикой Т самый математика так
began so cool, everything started in short, you have
классно да началось Всё короче у вас там
some stubborn mathematicians there in Ukraine
в Украине какие-то упоротые
Oh yes, deliver a live
математи размотали О да доставьте лайв
letter to my Telegram directly at once axis VN and
пись на мий Telegram прям зараз ось ВН а
Popik is more and more respectful YouTube
Попик це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
driving us through the skarg Orcs into your ban
загоняя нас через скарг Орки в твый бан
and  I don’t show too many videos to people
и дуже багато вдео не показую людям
at all times, I don’t show information about streams
вчасно не показуе информация про стримы
for this reason  Shchob mi Mali operational
тому для того щоб ми Мали оперативный
link write directly at once and while there in
звязок пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в
teleg okrim vdeo more tezh Tsikava and Korisna
teleg окрим вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and mi vinni z you trimati
информация и ми повинни з вами тримати
postiyny operational link
постийний оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine subscribe
YouTube Слава Украине подпишись